northampton.ac.uk 2019-05-02

# Privacy policy | University of Northampton

## About this policy

This policy explains what types of personal information will be gathered when you visit the University of Northampton’s website, and how this information will be used. Please note that this policy applies to the University’s main web pages (i.e. those in www.northampton.ac.uk).

Colleges, divisions, faculties, departments, institutes, academic services, libraries and collections of the University may run and maintain their own websites on the northampton.ac.uk domain (these will be identified as www.name.northampton.ac.uk or name.northampton.ac.uk). These sites may carry their own privacy policy or provide additional information relating to their activities, which will supersede or supplement this Privacy Policy.

If you follow a link to any other website, please check their policies before you submit any personal information to those websites.

## Information collected

On some parts of the website, you may be asked to provide some limited personal information in order to enable the provision of certain services (e.g. prospectus ordering, registering with a society, applying for a vacancy, etc). The University may store this information manually or electronically. By supplying this information you are consenting to the University holding and using it for the purposes for which it was provided. Information provided will be kept for as long as is necessary to fulfil that purpose.

We may also collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our digital services function. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns which does not identify any individual and allows us to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

### How the information collected is used

Personal information provided to the University by you will only be used for the purposes stated when the information is requested. Personal information will not be sold to third parties, or provided to direct marketing companies or other such organisations without your permission. Personal information collected and/or processed by the University is held in accordance with the the provisions of the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018.

Demographical and statistical information about user behaviour may be collected and used to analyse the popularity and effectiveness of the University’s website. Any disclosure of this information will be in aggregate form and will not identify individual users.

### How we store information collected

Information which you provide to us will ordinarily be stored on our secure servers. However, we do work with third party contractors, some of whom host and operate certain features of the website. Accordingly, information that we collect from you may be collected in or transferred to a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). That information may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our contractors. By submitting personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share such information in order to comply with any legal obligation or to protect the rights, property or safety of the University, its members or others.

## How we use “cookies”

Most of our web pages use “cookies”. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we place on your computer or mobile device if you agree. These cookies allow us to distinguish you from other users of our website, which helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allow us to improve our website.

For more detailed information on the cookies we use on the University’s main web pages (i.e. those in northampton.ac.uk) and the purposes for which we use them, please see our Cookie Statement. Please refer to individual web pages for further information about the use of cookies on other web pages on the northampton.ac.uk domain.

## Access to information

The provisions of the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR) and the Data Protection Act 2018 gives you the right to access information held about you. For further information about this right and how to exercise it, please see the University’s Policy on Data Protection.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email.

## Links

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that the University does not claim any responsibility for the privacy practices of such other sites. The University encourages users to be aware and read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

## Contact

Any queries or concerns about privacy on this website should be sent by email to [recordsmanager@northampton.ac.uk](mailto:recordsmanager@northampton.ac.uk) or addressed to the Records Management Office, University of Northampton, University Drive, Northampton NN1 5PH.
